March 10, 2021

Z Networks Oakland, CA Re: IT Technician

To whom it may concern,

I am very excited about the IT Technician position with Z Networks. I thoroughly reviewed the requirements of the position and feel confident that my experience as a Network Engineer, my recent Security+ certification, and my education background will allow me to perform well in the position.

I have always been passionate about technology ever since I jailbroke my iPod Touch when I was 12. My work experience in various IT positions such as Security Consultant and IT Consultant, as well as my Security+ and CCENT certifications are an indication of my continued interest in this field as I grew older. I am eager to continuously upgrade my knowledge and learn new skills as required and as opportunities arise to do so. This opportunity to wear multiple hats sounds very engaging to me.

In terms of my recent experience, after obtaining my undergraduate degree, I sought several contract positions which allowed me to learn a great deal about the diverse needs of various organizations. I am very interested in further expanding and sharpening my IT skills. As a Jr. Network Engineer, I deployed a 2008 Windows Server and a 2012 Windows Server both running Active Directory. Later as an IT Services Technician, I provided professional support for MacOS. I am also very familiar with Windows 8 and 10. I grew up in Oakland, thus am very familiar with the area, and am looking for a long-term role in the East Bay so that I can relocate back there as soon as possible.

I believe that my customer service experience and understanding of client needs, combined with my communication skills (oral, written and technical) will be very helpful in my success in this position. Furthermore, I have the ability to take initiative, manage my time efficiently and work successfully individually and with others. I believe that in view of my meticulousness, interpersonal skills, and integrity, I can successfully meet Z Network's work ethic, culture and philosophy.

I thank you for your time and consideration and would appreciate the opportunity of discussing this position and my background with you at your convenience.

Sincerely,

Daniel Krohn danielkrohn@pm.me (510) 830 - 9656

SUMMARY

A CompTIA Security+ and Cisco CCENT certified information security professional with a background in Network Engineering, Security Consulting, IT Operations, and Business Management. Technical experience is complemented with strong time / project management, communication, problem solving & client relationship skills as well as the highest level of ethics and professionalism.

EXPERIENCE

Certification & Other IT Skills Upgrade, June 2020 – Present

Worked at Chonmage Ramen House as a server and studied at night to:

- Obtain the CompTIA Security Plus, SY0-501, SEC+ Certification in December 2020.
- Learn Kali Linux operating system and Python programming language.

Security Consultant (Contract Position), CoreRisk Consulting, LLC, Mill Valley, CA, November 2019 – May 2020

- Successfully updated and maintained Cisco ASA 5500-X NGFW network security appliances.
- Designed and tested internal controls to ensure compliance with industry standard security frameworks, such as NIST and SSAE18 SOC 2.
- Provided advisory services surrounding network security and operations to 2 mid-tier organizations.

IT Consultant (Contract Position), Wu Wei Tea Temple, Fairfax, CA, April 2019 – October 2019

- Implemented and maintained the organization's information ecosystem, including the installation of network appliances, endpoints, and point-of-sales systems.
- Provided 24/7 on-call technology operations support, assessing the root cause of various technical failures and applying fixes as required such as software updates, patches and configuration management.

IT Services Technician (Contract Position), Bay Area Tech Hero, Oakland, CA, January 2019 – April 2019

- Installed, upgraded, and supported MacOS-based desktops and laptops.
- Troubleshooted and maintained network devices for small medium sized businesses.

Network Engineer (Contract Position), Presidio Inc., Woburn, MA, June 2018 – December 2018

- Configured, staged, tested and implemented a WAN co-location, consisting of a Nexus core with vPC, an MPLS edge, an internet edge, and links between the co-location and the client's new HQ.
- Assisted in the deployment of a greenfield LAN, including manual installations of ASR 1001-X Routers at the internet edge and Catalyst 9300 switch stacks among 9 IDFs
- Maintained complete technical documentation for network devices and processes surrounding the maintenance, implementation and configuration of those devices.

Junior Network Engineer (Contract Position), Aston Technologies, Brisbane, CA, February 2018 – May 2018

• Worked closely with Senior Network Engineers to design, configure and troubleshoot multiple network projects, including maintenance and implementation of security appliances.

EDUCATION / CERTIFICATIONS

- CompTIA Security Plus, SY0-501, SEC+ Certification, December 2020
- Cisco Certified Entry Networking Technician, CCENT Certification, June 2018
- California State University, Chico, BS in Accounting, May 2015

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Operating Systems: Windows 7-10, MacOS 11, iOS, Debian
- Computer Languages: Python, Java
- Software: Microsoft Office Suite, Active Directory, Wireshark, VMware, Virtual Box, Nmap
- Cisco Platforms: ASR 1001-X, Catalyst 9300, Nexus 93180YC, and ASA 5500-X NGFW
- OSI Layers & Protocols: **L4** (DNS, DHCP, RADIUS, TACACS+, Telnet/SSH, FTP/SFTP/FTPS), **L3** (EIGRP, OSPF. BGP, NAT), **L2** (STP, 802.1q, HSRP, vPC, LACP), **L1** (10/100/1000 Base-T, SMF, MMF, GLV, SFP, QSFP)